The hunt has evolved.
The Predator is a science fiction, action,
thriller film directed by Shane Black.
When a young boy accidentally triggers the universe's most lethal hunters' return to Earth, only a ragtag
crew of ex-soldiers and a disgruntled scientist can prevent the end of the human race.
Quinn McKenna, played by Boyd Holbrook.
Nebraska Williams, played by Trevante Rhodes.
Traeger, played by Sterling K. Brown.
Rory McKenna, played by Jacob Tremblay.
Coyle, played by Keegan-Michael Key.
Casey Brackett, played by Olivia Munn.
The Predator is a 2018 American science fiction action film directed
by Shane Black, who co-wrote it with Fred Dekker.
It is the fourth installment in the Predator
franchise, following Predators (2010).
The film stars Boyd Holbrook, Trevante Rhodes, Jacob Tremblay, Keegan-Michael
Key, Olivia Munn, Thomas Jane, Alfie Allen, and Sterling K.
It follows a group of PTSD-afflicted soldiers and a scientist who must team up to fight
off an invading pair of Predators and discover their plans for humankind.
Development of the film was announced in June 2014, with
Black being confirmed as writer and director.
Much of the cast signed on between October 2016 and January 2017.
Principal photography took place in British Columbia from February to June 2017, with the
climax being re-written and re-shot in July 2018 following poor test screenings.
The Predator premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 6, 2018,
and was released in the United States on September 14, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and
grossed $160 million against a budget of $88 million.
It was followed by a prequel, Prey, released in 2022 and a
sequel, Predator: Badlands released in 2025.
The film explores themes of predator, sequel, alien, creature, alien invasion.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.